[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to
tricentis tasa Advanced
Training as you all know I already
published 63 YouTube videos covering
beginners level intermediate level and
advanced level concepts of tricentis
tasa from couple of videos onwards have
started teaching you the realtime
scenarios where you might encounter
different types of
obstacles and how can we solve those
obstacles while automating your test
cases please do subscribe to the channel
click on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos this is lesson 64 in terms of
overall tricentis tasa automation
training and this is obstacle 22 in
terms of realtime
scenarios in this lesson I'm going to
teach you how can we solve an
obstacle to interact with the dynamic
table and how can you perform table
search for a specific cell value based
on your row and the column values by
using the buffer action mode and table
search methods now let us see in detail
what is the obstacle that we need to
solve
for so this is our obstacle that we are
going to solve for the obstacle name is
meeting Schuler and which is categorized
as easy so let us go for it to
understand the
obstacle so if you see here is the room
available on
Thursday 11 to 1
p.m. WR open or closed so you can see
here this table has the time schedules 9
to 11 11: 1 1 2 3 and 3 to 5 so
this so this particular column values
are constant these are not changing and
you also have The
Columns Monday Tuesday Wednesday
Thursday Friday but but the values
either the time slot is open or closed
for this particular day on this
particular time is dynamic so let me
refresh again okay if I
refresh so you can see here now on
Thursday from 11: to
13 now I can see
the schedule is open so it keeps on
changing it is not constant so basically
you need to enter whether the schedule
on Thursday from 11: to 13 is open or
closed so that's what we are going to
validate so now it is very easy to
automate the scenario why because we
already know that we have to consider a
row which has the
time period between 11 to 13 that means
the row is constant and also you have to
search for the availability on Thursday
itself that means your column is also
constant you know the row and you know
the column so it is very easy to
validate the schedule whether it is open
or closed on particular day so for that
let us go back to our trient
tosa and here as usual you need to right
click on obstacles
folder select scan and click on
application so this is the application I
would like to select select the
application click on
scan so here for this particular test
case we need to capture the web table
and edit box so this is my Tim
table is a web table and this is my
result
text select both of them now name the
module with the obstacle name simply
copy this obstacle name and paste the
obstacle name as module name now save
the
module and close your X scan so let us
go back to Tri and tasa so you can see
here now the new module whatever we
scanned which is this one 41
037 can see here you have time table and
then result text so let us go back to
our test case section
now as you all know we are capturing
every test case under obstacle folder so
in the same way for this obstacle as
well right click on obstacle folder test
case folder and select create test test
case and name this test case with the
same name as
obstacle okay and now double click on
this and go to your test case so to
start automating your test case I need
to drag this module and drop onto your
test
case now let's expand the test case so
here we already know that we need to
validate the the row which contains the
value 11 to 13 so I would like to copy
this value and here you need to Simply
provide the row name as 11 to13 so let's
do this 11 to 13 so I'm instructing
tasar to select the row which has the
value 11 to 13 so action mode is Select
and now what is the column that you need
to verify expand this cell you can see
here it is showing Monday Tuesday
Wednesday Thursday as per our use case
you need to see the availability on
Thursday so select the cell as or the
column as
Thursday right I'm selecting the column
as Thursday and
now as soon as it meets the criteria I
would like to store the value into a
buffer what I'm going to do here I'm
going to specify the buffer name
here
bore status what is the
status whether it is open or closed so
bore status is the buffer but here here
I'm not verifying it instead I'm
actually buffering it so I would like to
buffer the
value which is
available in row 11 to 13 and column
Thursday right so storing that into your
buffer and now I need to enter the same
thing
here whether it is open or closed
I'm going to call this buffer into a
edit box I'm going to enter the buffer
value in the edit box so open curly
braces capital B open Square
braces
bore
status close Square bra close curly
braces and your action mode is
input so now let us chain the work state
as
completed and save your test case now
let me execute the test case and see if
it
works right click and run in
scratchbook it entered open because on
Thursday 11 to 13 it is open that's why
it entered open hence your automation
problem solved successfully so let me
try this
again so now you can see here
now 11 to13 on Thursday your schedule is
closed let me run this if it works or
not we'll see right click and run in
scratchbook now it entered as closed you
can see here now it entered as closed
and your automation problem is solved
successfully so if you have any queries
leave your queries in the comment box
I'll try to respond to your queries hope
you all understand how can we solve an
obstacle where you need to interact with
the dynamic table and you need to
perform a table search for a specific
cell value based on the row and column
by using buffer action mode and table
search method please do subscribe to the
channel click on Bell icon you'll
receive notifications whenever I publish
more videos don't forget to like and
share the video
[Music]